Denis Quaid

Mobile Phone: 083 3147691 Email: denisq91@gmail.com Website: denisquaid.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/denis-quaid

Summary:

Highly versatile, entrepreneurial and results driven iOS developer with over seven years experience in mobile development using both Objective-C and Swift. Extremely determined, self-motivated and self-disciplined, able to make pragmatic decisions and pick up new concepts and technologies quickly.

I have an in-depth knowledge of the main Apple APIs and frameworks, building, testing and releasing iOS apps, as well as most common iOS architectures (MVC, MVVM, VIPER).

I make it my goal to create applications with the user in mind, creating applications with usable and intuitive user interfaces and suitable architectures which are up to date with the latest best practices.

Tools & Libraries:

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Tools: Git, Xcode, Testflight

Continuous Integration: Bitrise, Fastlane

Libraries: RxSwift, Realm, CocoaPods, SPM, UIKit, SwiftUI,, AlamoFire, XCTest, Firebase, Core Data,

Core Animation, Core Graphics, GCD

Work Experience:

Teamwork

iOS Developer (August 2017 - Present)

Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/teamwork/id1478913344

I joined Teamwork as we were beginning to rewrite an outdated Appcellerator app and replace it with a native Swift implementation. This involved hiring new members and working with the team to build a new app from the ground up using technologies such as RxSwift, Realm and using a VIPER architecture.

Throughout the last four years we have built and released the new app from scratch and released it to the App Store. My day to day work now involves enhancing features in the app according to the goals of the PM, monitoring crashes and analytics and fixing issues as they appear.

Some notable achievements include:

- Overseeing the development of the new VIPER architecture for the new generation of Teamwork's mobile iOS apps and wrote many of the main components using Swift, RxSwift and Realm.
- Designed and developed many of the reusable iOS backend service components that will be used on iOS projects and apps in the company.
- Undertaking the creation of a bespoke JSON API parsing library for all our iOS apps.

• Mentored and guided younger members of the team and introduced them to coding best practices.

YOOX NET-A-PORTER

iOS Developer (March 2015 - August 2017)

Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/net-a-porter-designer-fashion/id318597939

As part of the NET-A-PORTER iOS team I worked within part of the mobile team to deliver features and bug fixes in line with the current roadmap. My primary achievements include:

- Inheriting a completely Objective-C based application with less than 20% test coverage, after two years on the team this was raised to 45% and the majority of the app was ported to Swift 3.
- Took on the role of analytics champion within my team which meant I was the first point of contact for all analytics related work.
- Refactoring the previous analytics library in order to deliver a new library which conformed to the Customer Experience Digital Data Layer (CEDDL) which allows us to seamlessly port to different analytics providers.
- Delivered the first shoppable Apple TV application which was featured in Apple's Best of 2016. (https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/mr-porter/id481673241)

THE NET-A-PORTER GROUP

Graduate Software Developer (September 2014 - March 2015)

I began at Net-A-Porter as a graduate software developer where I worked within a front end web development team. I used this time to discover different software development languages and gain experience of working within an agile team of developers and testers. Achievements include:

- Created an application to dynamically generate a number of sitemaps for different categories and product pages on the Mr Porter website using Node.js and Express.js.
- Wrote unit tests to contribute to the test suite within the team and being part of the release process as a manual tester.
- During this time I also completed a number of online courses in order to improve my knowledge of software design practices and different languages.

Education:

BSC Social Science (2010-2013)

University College of Cork: Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)

MBS Electronic Business (2013-2014)

University College of Cork: Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)